我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me,
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
and one day I'll find who killed my mother...
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
- Mom. - and get justice for my father.
我就是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
罗尼
Ronnie!
那晚17人遇难  还有更多的人受伤
17 people died that night; many more were injured.
如今我在当地名声不见得有多好
I'm not the most popular person in town these days.
我们要适应
We're just supposed to get used to working
在关着超能力罪犯的临时监狱上面工作
above a makeshift prison housing evil people with superpowers.
这是什么
What is this?
一个你再也不能伤人的地方
Somewhere you'll never hurt anyone ever again.
十个月前
-法鲁克  -这样不安全
- Farooq! - It's not safe.
快下来
Come down.
法鲁克  我说真的
Farooq, I'm serious.
快下雨了
It's gonna rain.
你们都喝多了吧
Y'all are tripping.
这里可是屋里最棒的座位
This is the best seat in the house.
我说我们应该看着
You know, when I said we should watch
粒子加速器启动时
the particle accelerator turn on,
意思是我们应该脱光衣服在月光下嚎叫狂欢
I just meant we should get naked and howl at the moon.
已经启动了
It's already on.
我觉得不怎么样啊
Consider me unimpressed.
启动了  宝贝儿
Yeah, baby.
-简直太棒了  -你看到了吗
- This is awesome. - Are you seeing this?
天呐  我确实喝多了吧
Oh, man, I think I am tripping.
天呐
Oh, man.
快上车
Get in the car!
法鲁克
Farooq!
-法鲁克  -法鲁克
- Farooq! - Farooq!
闪电侠  第一季  第七集
日安  威尔斯博士
Good day, Dr. Wells.
希望如此  吉迪恩
One can always hope, Gideon.
调出我的日志好吗
Bring up my log, would you?
当然
Certainly.
请看  博士
Go ahead, Doctor.
输入新内容
New entry.
自从闪电袭击距今已经311天了
It has now been 311 days since lightning struck.
实验对象日常生活各方面都已开始
Subject has begun relying on his speed
依赖于自己的速度
in everyday life,
他使用自己超凡的能力
using his extraordinary powers
解决日常问题...
to solve ordinary problems...
要迟到了
I'm late.
完成日常工作和任务
And accomplish ordinary tasks.
不幸的是  他一直想做一个英雄
Unfortunately, his penchant for the heroic persists.
早上客人这么多他们还来训练新人
I hate it when they let the new guy train
真是太烦人了
during the morning rush.
-你也有了吗  -有了
- Did you get one too? - Yeah.
事实是...
The fact is...
不要动
Don't try nothing.
他有点炫耀自己的能力
He can be a bit of a showoff.
把钱包给我  马上
Wallet. Now.
真是太棒了  你跟我开玩笑对吧
Oh, this is awesome. You've got to be kidding me.
等一下好吗  我先...
Hold on, okay? I'm just gonna--
我先把咖啡放下
I'm gonna set this down.
太巧了吧
I mean, this is crazy.
说实话中城有
There are literally hundreds of thousands
成千上万的人
of people in Central City,
你可以抢劫任何人  可你偏偏选中了我
and out of everyone you could have picked to rob, you pick me.
说什么  你神经病吗  快给我钱
What, are you sick? Money, now.
我...你这真的是在自讨苦吃  老兄
I just--you're really gonna be kicking yourself, man.
如果有奥运会是比赛谁运气最差的
I mean, if there was an Olympics for bad luck,
你拿到的可不止是奖牌  老兄
you didn't just medal, pal.
简直就是菲尔普斯附体
You Michael Phelps-ed.
我数三下  你再不给我我就开枪了
I'll count to three. Then I'm gonna shoot you.
-1  -好
- One... - Yeah.
Two.
虽然他想帮助别人这点值得赞扬
And while his desire to help others is commendable,
但是这也阻碍了他
it is impeding him from realizing
全面理解自己的能力
the full scope of his abilities.
但未来并没有改变
But there's still time,
《中城时报》
危机降临  闪电侠失踪
所以我们还有时间
as the future remains intact.
巴里在哪里  他迟到了
Where's Barry? He's late.
迟到是他的招牌
Late is kind of his signature move.
你们想不想看看我的招牌
Hey, you guys want to see my signature move?
不好意思  大伙  我有点事耽搁了
Sorry, guys, I got a little held up.
我必须得在那帮忙
You had to be there.
我要和巴里单独谈谈
I'm gonna need a moment or two alone with Barry.
你要遭殃了哦
You're in trouble.
让我提醒你一下  艾伦先生
Now, may I remind you, Mr. Allen,
我们有过协议
we had an agreement.
我们帮你在外面维持英雄形象
We would help with your heroics out there
作为交换  你要帮助我们进行研究
while you would help us research and develop
并且充分发展你的潜能  对吧
your abilities in here, right?
是  我知道
Yeah. No, I know.
我想我可能
I-I guess I've just
对帮助他人这事有点上瘾了
gotten a little caught up with being able to help people,
把坏人一网打尽什么的
you know, put bad guys away.
这样感觉很好
It feels good.
想象一下  如果能治愈疾病
Imagine how good it will feel
延缓衰老  治疗瘫痪  那感觉会有多好
to cure diseases, stop aging, reverse paralysis.
这些都是好事
All good causes.
那我要怎么帮你
So how can I help you do that?
你是要我多做几次核磁共振  多抽点血...
You need more MRIs, more blood, or--
-我需要更快的速度  -好吧
- I need more speed. - Okay.
速度是一切的核心
Speed is the key to progress.
你得加把劲才行
You need to kick it up a notch.
刚刚发生了一场谋杀案
There was a homicide.
很抱歉  我得走了
I'm sorry. I've got to go.
这事不仅仅关系到你
This is not just about you.
记住这点  巴里
Remember that, Barry.
但愿你们都没吃早餐
I hope you both skipped your breakfast.
谁能干得出这种事
What the hell could do that?
2400华氏度的大火就能
2,400 degrees, give or take.
这片区域都是易燃物
This area's filled with combustibles.
为什么其他的东西没烧起来
How come nothing else burned up?
你要去哪里
Where you going?
你看到水泥地被烧焦后留下的痕迹吗
You see the soot on the ground where the cement is burnt?
-看到了  -那是电弧爆炸的证据
- Yeah. - That's evidence of arc blasts.
当高倍数的电流通过空气
Happens when high-amperage currents
传播或放出电弧时就会留下这些痕迹
travel or arc through the air.
这附近没有电线
There's no live wires.
也没有电线杆
There's no utility poles.
那这个人是怎么被电死的
So how was this guy electrocuted?
我们首先得找出他的身份
Well, the first thing we need to do is I.D. him.
他的脸都糊成一团了
His face is melted off.
你拍照片怎么可能找得出他的身份呢
How's that picture gonna help I.D. him?
我厉害着呢
I got mad skills.
别再说这句话了
Please don't ever say that again.
好吧
All right.
你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
我没事  怎么了
Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
你看起来有点心不在焉
I don't know. You seem a little off.
-我没事  -那就好
- No, I'm fine. - All right.
这个面部识别软件
Facial recognition software--
是为考古学家设计的
it's designed for archeologists,
它应该能搞清楚你那酥脆的死者的身份
and it should help us I.D. your crispy corpse.
问题是  他是怎么被电成这样的
The question is, how did he get fried in the first place?
难道说还有能控制电力的超能力者
Is there a metahuman out there that can control electricity?
要造成这种程度的组织损坏
It'd take a serious electrostatic discharge
需要大幅度放电
to cause that level of tissue damage.
根据软件的处理结果
Guys, according to the software,
死者有82%的可能性长这样
there's an 82% chance your victim looked like this.
才82%
82%?
你来的时候这个可能性还是零呢
Hey, it was zero when you walked in here, pal.
把它和车管所的数据库交叉对比
Can you cross-reference that with the DMV database,
看看能不能找到名字
maybe get a name?
没问题
Absolutely.
自从费莉西蒂重新编写过这个软件
This software can do just about anything
它就变得无所不能了
now that Felicity reprogrammed it.
驾驶证  凯西·多纳休
凯西·多纳休
Casey Donahue.
无妻无子
No wife. No kids.
曾经在彼得斯堡变电站工作
Used to work at the Petersburg Electrical Substation.
-这绝非巧合  -真奇怪
- That can't be a coincidence. - That's weird.
有人刚刚用他的名牌进入了变电站
Someone just used his I.D. to enter the substation.
彼得斯堡电网的能量被吸收了
The Petersburg grid is experiencing a power drain
就现在
right now.
巴里
Barry, be...
小心
careful.
我很确定这里是禁区
I'm pretty sure this is a restricted area.
冷静  活泼小子
Easy there, zappy.
我必须吸食能量
I have to feed.
怎么回事
Whoa, what was that?
还要
More of that.
我还要
I need more.
巴里  发生什么了
Barry, what's happening?
太多了
Too much.
快离开
Get out of there.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry.
我不行
I can't.
我的速度
My speed...
没了
is gone.
他比正常人跑得都慢
He runs slow even for a normal person.
你不可能就这么丢失能量的
You can't just lose your powers, okay?
你的基因是由于粒子加速器爆炸才改变的
Your DNA was transformed by the particle accelerator blast.
基因是不可能被变回去的
There's no way to untransform DNA.
是啊  你去跟那个收了我65块钱
Yeah, tell that to the uber driver
载我到这里的司机说这些话吧
who charged me 65 bucks to take me here.
我只能告诉她  我从变装派对出来的
I had to tell her I was coming from a cosplay party.
这么说我们错了
So we were wrong.
这个超能力者不是用电致人死亡
This meta-human doesn't electrocute people.
他吸收电能  从而带走了你的能力
He siphons electricity, thereby removing your power.
好吧  那这是暂时的还是...
All right, do we think this is temporary or--
得做几个测试才能知道
We have to run tests.
好吧
Yeah.
我得去提醒乔
I've got to warn Joe.
巴里  我们会找到恢复你速度的办法的
Barry, we will find a way to restore your speed.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
-你没接住  -我超爱那个马克杯的
- You didn't catch it. - I loved that mug.
我的速度被超能力者偷走了
And what part of the meta-human stole my speed?
你没听明白吗
Didn't you understand?
巴里  你做的那些事里
Barry, there's no part of anything you can do
没有一件是我能明白的
that I ever understand.
威尔斯博士怎么说
What does Dr. Wells say?
他正在研究
He's working on it.
巴里  你必须夺回你的速度
Barry, you have to get your speed back.
这座城市里的人需要保护
People in this city need protecting,
如果你的速度回不来了
and if you don't get your speed,
我们要怎么确保他们的安全呢
how the hell are we gonna keep them safe?
乔  偷了我速度的超能力者
Joe, the meta who stole my speed,
是他把我们今天在小巷看到的尸体烧掉的
he burned up the body we saw in the alley today.
你必须告诉警局的人不要和他正面冲突
You need to tell the police not to confront him.
-他很危险  -谁很危险
- He's dangerous. - Who's dangerous?
没什么  就是个小偷
No one, just some thief.
罪犯们最好小心了
Well, criminals better watch out.
中心城市的警察是最优秀的
Cops in Central City are the best there are,
如果你们不能保护这个城市  爸爸
and if you can't protect this city, dad,
我知道闪电侠会的
I know the Flash will.
如果他不能呢
What if he can't?
如果他消失了呢
What if he's gone?
消失
Gone?
是啊  可能他的工作结束了
Yeah, or maybe he's just done,
或者有些事过去他可以做
or maybe it's like whatever he could do before,
现在不能做了
he can't do anymore.
巴里
Barry?
你不是要去什么地方吗
Don't you have someplace to be?
是啊  这就走
Yeah, going.
巴里超爱那个马克杯的
Aw, Barry loved that mug.
那是块好表啊  年轻人
That's a quality time piece, young man.
谢谢
Uh, thanks.
他们把我的夺走了
They took mine,
全部夺走了
all of them.
你不该犯事儿
I guess you shouldn't have done
不然表就不会被没收了
whatever it is you did.
走吧
Come on.
吉迪恩  给我看未来
Gideon, show me the future.
好的  博士
Certainly, Doctor.
退还给寄件人
美国邮局关闭寄存处
全面搜索
Run a complete search.
给我看有关闪电侠的所有资料
Show any references to the Flash.
未找到和闪电侠相关的资料
Zero references to the Flash.
再找
Look again.
没有资料
Zero references.
给我看有关巴里·艾伦的所有资料
Show any references to Barry Allen.
未找到和巴里·艾伦相关的资料
Zero references to Barry Allen.
再查一遍
Look again!
我已经查了3452遍  威尔斯博士
I've searched 3,452 times, Dr. Wells.
未找到结果
There's nothing.
你觉得我还会穿上这套衣服吗
You think I'll ever wear it again?
我觉得会的
I hope so.
我拥有这个速度的时间不长
I didn't have my speed for very long,
可一旦这个能力不见了
but now that it's gone,
感觉我自己的一部分也被掏空了
it feels like part of me is gone too.
不管有没有速度  你都是你  巴里
With or without your speed, you're still you, Barry.
但我不是了
But I'm not.
我不是最好的我
I'm not the best version of me.
我喜欢当闪电侠
I love being the Flash.
我喜欢作为闪电侠的一切
I love everything about it:
喜欢那种每小时可以跑几百英里的感觉
the feeling of running hundreds of miles per hour,
风和其它能量拂过面庞的感觉
wind and power just rushing past my face,
能够帮助他人的感觉
being able to help people.
失去了这些我都不知道该怎么办  凯特琳
I'm not sure I can live without it, Caitlin.
-法鲁克·吉布朗  -谁
- Farooq Gibran. - Who?
就是那个抢走你的速度的吸能鬼
The powers vampire who jacked your speed.
我黑进了彼得斯堡变电站的
I hacked into the surveillance footage
监控录像系统
from the Petersburg Substation.
只要看清他的长相  就不难查出来这是谁
Once I got his face, it was easy to find a match.
粒子加速器爆炸那晚
He climbed an electrical tower
他爬上了一架电塔
the night of the accelerator explosion.
那么他有超能力也不奇怪了
No surprise where his powers came from.
这不是真的吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
怎么会发生这种事
This is not happening.
哈里森·威尔斯博士
Dr. Harrison Wells,
我要见你
I need to see you!
出来  我知道你在里面  开门
Come on, I know you're inside. Open the door.
我只想谈谈  威尔斯博士
I just want to talk, Dr. Wells.
威尔斯
Wells!
让我进去
Let me in!
乔
Joe.
你好  爱瑞丝
Hello, Iris.
我下班了
I am out.
换班之前就交给你了
I need you to cover for me until the shift change.
只有一件要紧事  囚犯转移
Only one headline, prison transfer,
威廉姆·塔克曼
William Tockman.
把枪放下
Guns on the floor!
你们用不了三秒就能想明白
It should take you less than three seconds
是该服从  还是做无谓的反抗
to discard any thought of rebellion and comply.
我想我不用大声地报数吧
I take it I don't need to count out loud.
长得可真像啊
Striking resemblance.
他已经进来了
He's inside.
队长
Captain,
塔克曼至少挟持了十名人质
Tockman has at least ten hostages.
两名警官已中枪
Two officers down.
收到  电力什么时候恢复
Copy that. When is the power back?
我们正在设置发电机
We're on gennies for now.
-现在没空  -等等
- Not now. - Wait.
辛格队长  我一直想联系上乔
Captain Singh, I've been trying to get in touch with Joe
或者其他辖区内的人
or anyone at the precinct.
有人质被挟持了  巴里
There's a hostage situation, Barry,
乔就在里面
and Joe's inside.
还有他的女儿
So's his daughter.
一旦知道更多信息  我就打给你
I'll call you when I know more.
等等
Wait--
乔和爱瑞丝有麻烦了
Joe and Iris are in trouble.
我得恢复我的能力
I need my powers back now.
我有个想法
I have a theory.
但它并未得到过证实
It's untested.
我愿意赌一把
I'm willing to roll the dice.
好的  你的确失去了能力
Okay, you've lost your speed, yes,
但从亚原子水平上来说  你的身体并未有所改变
but nothing has changed inside you on a subatomic level.
换句话说  你的细胞仍然处于活跃状态
In other words, your cells are still primed.
它们只需要一个激发源
They just need a jumpstart.
那我们怎么办  怎么激发我
Okay, how do we do that? How do we jumpstart me?
我们需要重现你的身体曾受到的冲击
We need to replicate the initial jolt to your system.
可是那就意味着要对他
But that would mean a peak current
施加的峰值电流至少为两千万安培
of at least 20,000 kilo-amps.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
这比电椅用的电量
That's more electricity than they give to people
都还要大
in the electric chair.
凯特琳  法鲁克已经进了这幢楼
Caitlin, with Farooq in the building,
我们也只有死的可能了
we're all looking at a death sentence here.
我们并未启用备用发电机
The spare generator's offline.
如果重新启动  也许可以提供所需电压
If we reboot it, we could get a charge that big.
我们需要想办法把发动机
We need something that can transmit the load
产生的电量丝毫不减地
from the generator to Barry's body
输入到巴里的身体里
without shorting out.
用跑步机
The treadmill.
我的宝贝承受得住这种电量
My baby could take the charge.
如果巴里受不了呢
What if Barry can't?
这就得看艾伦先生了
Well, that's up to Mr. Allen.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要去跟他谈
I'm gonna talk to him.
不  不行
No. No.
你没看到他在变电站的样子
Okay, you didn't see him at the substation.
他需要吸食能量
He needed to feed.
粒子加速器爆炸后  我获得了速度
I got super speed out of the particle accelerator blast,
可他失去了两位好朋友
but his best friends died.
醒来后身体就出了问题
He woke up with a disease.
今天早上  你还在犯罪现场
Earlier today, you worked a crime scene
这个超能力者电死了一个无辜受害者
where this metahuman electrocuted an innocent man.
他是杀人犯
He's a murderer!
而你没有任何能力与他对抗
And you are powerless to defend yourself against him.
他也许只是像我当初一样需要帮助
He may just need help like I did.
我不需要能力就可以帮他
I don't need my powers to offer him that.
我必须试试
I have to try.
塔克曼
Tockman?
Tockman.
塔克曼
Tockman!
现在这里由我掌控
I am presently in control
在场有八位中城精英
of eight of Central City's finest,
三位低薪资的助理
three underpaid assistants,
还有一位勇敢的平民女孩
and one very brave civilian girl.
你有要求  可以讲来听听
You've got demands; I want to hear them.
不过先把人放出来
But first let the civilians go.
你希望我让他们横着出去还是竖着出去
Would you prefer I sent them out alive or dead?
你说清楚点
Please be more specific.
一架直升飞机  一份素食外带套餐
One helicopter, one vegetarian takeout meal,
还有一台8GB内存的笔记本电脑
one laptop with eight gigabytes of RAM
要在53分27秒后
will be delivered on this roof at exactly 53 minutes
送到屋顶
and 27 seconds from now,
否则我就杀一个人质
or I shoot a hostage.
整个城市都停电了
There is a citywide blackout.
我需要更多时间
I'm gonna need more time.
队长  送你一句话  时不我待
Captain, you may delay, but time will not.
本杰明·富兰克林说的
Benjamin Franklin.
非常好  警探
Very good, Detective.
放轻松
Whoa, whoa, easy.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
你伤害不了我
You can't hurt me.
哈里森·威尔斯在哪里
Where is Harrison Wells?
我知道你遭遇了什么
Look, I know what happened to you.
粒子加速器爆炸的那晚改变了你
The night of the accelerator explosion, it changed you.
也改变了我
It changed me too.
你就是穿红衣的那个人
You were the one in the red suit.
我吸食了你的能量
I fed from you.
我必须继续吸食
I have to keep feeding.
我知道你觉得很害怕
All right, I know this has to be terrifying.
所以我才想帮你
That's why I want to help you, okay?
那晚的爆炸  我被那束光击中的时候
The night of the explosion, when the light hit me,
心跳都停止了
it stopped my heart.
杰克和达雅
Jake and Darya--
是你的朋友
They were your friends.
我醒来时  他们躺在我旁边  死了
I woke up, and they were beside me, dead.
他们想给我用心肺复苏术
They tried to give me CPR.
他们碰了我
They were touching me,
却被我电死了
and I electrocuted them.
这不是你的错
This is not your fault.
我知道
I know.
是威尔斯干的
Wells did this to me.
法鲁克  你得听我说
Farooq, you need to listen to me.
不知道能挡他多久
Not sure how long that will hold.
圣母心破碎了吗  艾伦先生
Done being noble, Mr. Allen?
凯特琳  送他去跑步机
Caitlin, get him to the treadmill.
西斯科  去启动发电机
Cisco, bring the generator online.
确保巴里能吸收足够的电量
Make sure Barry gets the charge.
什么  你不跟我一起来吗
What? You're not coming with me?
我不会丢下你
I am not leaving you.
听我说
Listen to me.
在我一生做过的所有事情中
Of everything I've done in my life,
发明的所有东西中
of everything I have invented,
最重要的创作就是闪电侠
My most important creation is the Flash.
巴里·艾伦一定要有未来
Barry Allen must have a future.
现在赶紧走
Now, go.
走
Go!
赶快停止这一切  我会跟地检求情
End this now, and I'll talk to the D.A.
就是你的地方检察官驳回了我的休假申请
It was your district attorney that denied me furlough
以至于我不能见我快死的妹妹最后一面
so I could visit my dying sister one last time,
不能亲自跟她道别
say good-bye to her in person.
那是我再也回不去的时间
That's time I'll never get back!
所以不论我这一生还剩多少时间
So however long I have in this life,
我发誓再也不要
I promise not one second more
在监狱中度过
will be spent in a prison cell.
打中他了
Got him.
艾迪
Eddie!
艾迪  艾迪  艾迪
Eddie. Eddie, Eddie.
一位警官刚在9.2秒之前被击中
An officer was just shot 9.2 seconds ago.
你们要加快速度满足我的要求了  队长
I'd pick up the pace in meeting my demands, Captain.
我不再能快速恢复了
I'm not healing fast anymore.
-那太糟糕了  -别担心
- That's unfortunate. - Don't worry.
一旦威尔斯博士有主意  他一般都是正确的
When Dr. Wells has a theory, he's usually right.
万一乔和爱瑞丝出什么事了怎么办
What if something happens to Joe and Iris first?
过来看看你的宠物过得好不好吗
Come to check on your pet?
你为什么不直接杀了我
Why don't you just kill me, huh?
一劳永逸
Get it over with.
[拉丁语]
Quid pro quo.
我刚说的是拉丁语  伍德沃德先生
That's Latin, Mr. Woodward.
你听说过拉丁语吗
You've heard of Latin?
这句话是说用某样东西换取另一样东西
Quid pro quo means something for something,
现在说的某样东西指的是你的自由
and in this case that something is your freedom.
我准备给你自由
I'm prepared to grant it to you.
你怎么知道我不会杀了你
How do you know I won't kill you?
我们就称它为预测风险好了
Let's call that a calculated risk,
这是我愿意承担的风险
one I'm willing to take.
-真的吗  -千真万确
- Really? - That's right.
你为什么要那么做
Why would you do that?
因为有另一个超能力者
Because there is another Metahuman
在这幢大楼里
loose in this facility.
我要你杀了他
I want you to kill him.
你知道人体能发电吗
Did you know the human body generates electricity?
平均每人会发电大约342瓦
The average person gives off 342 Watts,
我可以感受到你们身上散发的电量
and I can smell it coming from you.
-开启跑步机  -你还伤着
- Turn on the treadmill. - You're still hurt.
我们没时间了
We don't have time!
想死揍人的感觉了
Been dying to punch somebody.
-凯特琳  -我做不到
- Caitlin! - I can't.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
如果我开了  你会死的
If I turn this on, it could kill you.
如果你不开  我们都会死的
If you don't, we could all die.
在这幢楼里我已经失去了一个我很珍惜的人
I already lost someone I cared about in this building.
我不能再失去一次
I can't do it again.
听着  曾经有人告诉我
Listen, someone once told me
我被闪电击中是有原因的
that I was struck by that lightning for a reason,
是命运选择了我
that it chose me.
我不觉得我相信这话
I'm not sure I believe it.
现在  重要的不是我相信什么
Right now, it doesn't matter what I believe.
而是你相信什么
What do you believe?
来吧
Come on.
天呐  你还好吗
My god, are you okay?
你感觉到什么了吗
Did you feel anything?
这没奏效
It didn't work.
求求你  他在流血
Please, he's bleeding.
你要让我们帮帮他
You have to let us get him some help.
你待着别动
You'll stay where you are.
在你消磨时间的时候  他会流血而亡的
And while you're killing time, he's bleeding out.
宛如你可以消磨时间而不伤害永恒一样
As if you could kill time without wounding eternity.
亨利·戴维·梭罗[美国作家哲学家]
Henry David Thoreau.
不错
Ooh, good.
战场小技巧
A little battlefield trick.
艾迪
Eddie.
如果他能撑到医疗救治
If he lives long enough to receive medical treatment,
他们会知道止血带是什么时候绑上的
they'll know the exact time the tourniquet was applied.
怎么  不谢谢我吗
What? No thank you?
他们称你为同步信号之王  对吧
They call you the Clock King, right?
也就是华丽的称谓而已
A somewhat florid appellation,
但是我已经可以看到个中幽默之处
but I've grown to see the humor in it.
你会被送回监狱的
You're going back to prison.
真的吗
Really?
你怎么知道的
And--and how do you reckon?
因为闪电侠正在赶过来
Because the Flash is coming.
你在哪呢
Oh, where are you?
托尼
Tony.
托尼  你在干什么
Hey, Tony, what are you doing?
你了解我的  艾伦
Oh, come on. You know me, Allen.
我打架从不投降
I never run from a fight.
好吧  坚持住
All right, well, stay with me, okay?
你没事的
You're good.
快跑
Run.
什么
What?
托尼
Hey, Tony.
不要
No.
巴里
Barry.
早了
Early.
你有在晚上坐直升机看过这座城吗
You ever seen the city at night by helicopter?
美妙至极
It's quite spectacular.
你气喘吁吁的  这可不妙
You're winded. That's not good.
我需要采集你的血液来分析原因
I need to take your blood and figure out what happened.
我不敢相信他竟然死了
I can't believe he's dead.
威尔斯博士吗
Dr. Wells?
不不  托尼·伍德沃德
No, no. Tony Woodward.
他从军火补给站逃出来了
He escaped from the pipeline.
他肯定是在停电时逃出来的
He must have got out when the blackout hit.
不可能
Not possible.
军火补给站被设计好  可以在停电时运转
The pipeline was designed to withstand a power outage.
肯定有人放他出来的
Someone had to have let him go.
是我
I did.
是我放了他
I released him.
为什么
Why?
为了转移那入侵者的注意力
To divert our intruder's attention
好让我们想办法恢复你的速度
while we worked to restore your speed.
你用他来当诱饵
You used him as a distraction?
没想到是多余的一步
An unnecessary one, as it turns out.
看来计划失败了
It seems the plan has failed.
他是因我而死的
I have his blood on me.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do that?
你对在童年时欺凌你的人
You're showing a lot of sentiment for a man
还挺有同情心的
who tormented you as a child.
托尼也许一直是个恶霸
Tony might have been a bully then and now,
可他也不能这样去送死啊
but he didn't deserve to die.
那凯特琳  西斯科  我或者你
Does Caitlin or Cisco or me
就要去死吗
or you?
我需要做出选择  他还是我们
I had a choice to make, him or us.
我毫不犹豫地选择了我们
I chose us without a second thought.
你总是在谈奇迹般的解药
Well, all your talk about miracle cures
还有科学突破
and scientific breakthroughs,
但你却完全不关心别人
but you don't care about people at all.
也许是你关心的太多了  巴里
Well, maybe you care too much, Barry.
我知道英雄这个身份对你很重要
I know being a hero is important to you,
我也尊重你的理想
and I respect your ideals.
我只是没那个福分拥有这个理想
I just don't have the luxury of sharing them.
我忘了
I forgot.
你只是在玩国际象棋
Your game's chess.
我们都是你的小卒  对吧
We're all just pawns to you, right?
那你准备怎么下  博士
So what's your move, Doctor?
接下来你又要牺牲谁
Which one of us gets sacrificed next?
我们必须逃出这里
We have to get out of the facility.
我们刚在D层甩掉他
We just left him on D level.
我们从这里肯定到不了正门
We'll never make it to the main entrance from here.
那车库呢  移动实验室箱车
What about the garage, the mobile lab van?
轮到我说话了  艾伦先生
It's my move, Mr. Allen,
要我说  我们得试一试
and I say we make a run for it.
天呐  巴里  快看
Oh, my God. Barry, look.
你的细胞正在快速修复
Your cells, they're rapidly regenerating.
我还是没找回速度
I still don't have my speed.
肯定是精神上的问题  不是肉体的
It must be mental, not physical.
你有投球失忆症了
Oh, you have the yips.
-什么症  -你知道的
- The whats? - You know.
当二垒手突然扔不到一垒
When a second baseman all of a sudden can't throw to first
或是高尔夫球手想要轻推进球
or a golfer tries to putt
他们会感到窘迫和沮丧
and they get all embarrassed and upset,
于是投球失忆症恶化
and then that makes the yips worse,
然后就变得一团乱
and it's a hot mess,
他们就感到更加失败了
and then they feel like even more of a failure.
你说这些一点帮助没有
That's not helping.
你问我是否相信
Look, you asked if I believed
你被闪电击中是有原因的
you were struck by lightning for a reason,
你是否刚好被选中了
if you were chosen.
我相信你是对的
I believe.
你也应该相信
You should too.
走吧
Let's move.
塔克曼  不要
Tockman, no.
不  别这样  别带她走
No, don't do this, not her.
不  带我走吧  求你
No, take me, please.
我怎么觉得你好像不会当个温顺的乘客呢
Something tells me you will not be a docile passenger.
-但她会  -爸爸  爸爸
- She will. - Dad. Dad.
等等  让她道个别吧
Wait, wait! Let her say good-bye.
躺在这里快死掉的是她男朋友
This is her boyfriend lying here dying,
我想你我都明白他可能撑不了很久了
and I think you and me both know that he probably won't make it.
当时没有给你机会和妹妹说再见是不对的
It's wrong that you didn't get to say good-bye to your sister.
别让他们留下同样的遗憾
Give them what you deserved.
给你20秒
You have 20 seconds.
艾迪  艾迪
Eddie. Eddie.
抱歉  宝贝
Sorry, babe.
不  求你
No, please.
你要为我撑下去  好吗
You have to hang on for me, okay?
我马上就回来
I'm gonna be right back.
走了
Let's go.
第二辆货车  钥匙在车里
Second van, keys are inside.
快
Come on.
快上车  快
Get in! Come on!
他来了
He's here.
巴里
Barry.
快
Quickly.
时间不等人
Time and tide wait for no man.
等等  让她道个别吧
Wait, let her say good-bye.
给你20秒
You have 20 seconds.
脚踝枪套
Ankle Holster.
爱瑞丝
Iris!
天呐  你没事吧
Oh, my God, are you okay?
我没事
I'm okay.
两位
Guys.
天呐
Oh, my God.
天呐  不要  求你
Oh, my God. No, please.
你
Hey!
你是来找我的
You're here for me.
你终于露面了
Finally you show your face.
我确实不是很想死
Well, I wasn't exactly eager to be killed.
我朋友们也不想
Neither were my friends.
我知道
I know.
那晚我伤害了许多人
I hurt a lot of people that night.
许多人
People?
你连他们的名字都不知道吧
You don't even know their names.
杰克·达文波特
Jake Davenport.
金达雅
Darya Kim.
拉尔夫·德比  阿尔·罗思坦
Ralph Dibny, Al Rothstein,
格兰特·爱默生  威尔·埃弗雷特
Grant Emerson, Will Everett,
贝尔·德·卡斯塔  罗尼·雷蒙德
Bea Da Costa, Ronnie Raymond.
我记得那晚遇难的所有人的名字
I know the names of every person who died that night.
我知道他们每个人都很有价值
I know they all mattered,
而这世界失去了他们未来的可能性
and the fact that the world is now deprived of their potential
是我要永远背负的罪
is something that I have to live with every day,
但他们  犯错误的不是他们
but these people -- these people have done nothing wrong.
你想要惩罚我
You want to punish me?
可以  那尽管来吧
Fine, let's do that,
但是别杀他们
but let these people live.
就当那晚你也死了
You died that night too.
不
No!
只是今天你才知道
You just didn't know it till today.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
我们可以叫他断电吗
We could have called him Blackout?
他有名字的  西斯科
He had a name, Cisco.
我还不知道到底发生了什么
I'm just not sure what happened.
他为什么没像之前那样吸取我的能量呢
Why didn't he just siphon all my powers like before?
因为你终于不再想着你的力量
Because you finally stopped thinking about your powers
而是和它成为了一体
and just connected to them.
看  这是你刚被闪电
Look, this is a sample of your blood
击中时的一份血样
from just after you were struck by lightning.
你的细胞产生的能量比以前任何状态都多
Now your cells are generating more energy than ever before.
多到了那个超能力者没法安全控制的地步
It was more energy than the meta could safely handle.
就像是他吸取时被呛住了的感觉
It's almost like he choked on you.
这又是什么意思
But what does that mean?
意思是你又进步了许多
It means you've kicked it up a notch.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
关于我之前说你不在乎别人  我
What I said about how you don't care about people, I--
不  听着  巴里
No, look, Barry.
我的传记里把我描述成自大
There is a reason that my biography describes me
尖刻而又无礼  是有原因的
as arrogant, prickly, brusque--
有时还有些傲慢
At times contemptuous?
-我看了两遍  -你说得没错
- I read it twice. - You were right.
我不太关心其他人  巴里
I don't care much for people, Barry.
我觉得他们误传信息  目光短浅
I find them misinformed, shortsighted.
那你为什么还要这么做
So why do you do what you do?
为什么大半夜还不睡
Why get up in the morning?
因为我相信未来会更好
Because I believe in a better future,
那个我很想看到的未来
one that I very much want to see,
那个有你参与的未来
one that you are a part of.
也许我不太关心其他人  巴里
I might not much care for people, Barry,
但是我关心你
but I care about you.
创伤小组呼叫重症监护室
Trauma team to the NICU.
艾伦
Hey, Allen.
艾迪
Hey, Eddie.
你还带花来了
Flowers.
太好了
That's so nice.
你整晚都去哪了
Where were you all night?
在家里  在冰淇淋融化之前吃光它们
Home, trying to eat all the ice cream before it melted.
我很喜欢冰淇淋
I love ice cream.
他吃了很多的止痛药
He is on pain meds, lots of them,
但是他不会有事的
but he's gonna be okay.
惊险的一晚
It's been some night.
我去买杯咖啡
I am gonna get some coffee.
马上回来
I'll be back.
老兄
Dude.
太棒了
Awesome.
看来你好多了
I guess you're feeling better.
是的
Oh, yeah.
你们看到刚才那一幕了吗
Did you guys see that?
你刚吃了药  伙计
You're just high, partner.
没错  我都忘了
Right, I forgot.
你现在才来
Oh, now you show up.
对不起  今天没能救你
I'm sorry I wasn't there for you today.
-我自顾不暇  -没关系
- It couldn't be helped. - It's okay.
有时我们得做自己的英雄  拯救自己
A girl's got to be her own hero every now and again.
我保证不会再迟到
I promise I'll never be late again.
我的好朋友总是这么说
My best friend is always saying that,
结果他总是迟到
and he is always late.
你值得我准时出现
You're worth being on time for.
宝贝  没事吧
Honey, you all right?
没事  怎么了
Yeah, why?
你忘记买咖啡了
You forgot your coffee.
日安  威尔斯博士
Good day, Dr. Wells.
日安  吉迪恩
Yes, it is, Gideon.
请调出我的日志  新条目
Bring up my log, please, new entry.
闪电击中至今已经过了312天
It has now been 312 days since lightning struck.
过去的24小时里
In the past 24 hours,
实验对象已经取得了巨大的飞跃
subject has taken a great leap forward,
让我修改了我最初的论文
causing me to revise my initial thesis.
我以为
I thought--
我以为他对别人的依恋
Well, I thought his attachment to people
会令他分心  并减慢他的进步
was a distraction slowing down his progress.
而现在我意识到事实正好相反
Now I realize the opposite is true.
巴里对别人的依恋  他所在乎的人
Barry's attachment to people, the people he cares about,
才是促进他飞速的关键
is actually the key to getting him up to speed.
同时
In the meantime,
《中城时报》
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
还有一个好消息
good news.
未来仍然完好无损
The future remains intact.
你早到了
You're early.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我也觉得很奇怪
It feels weird to me too.
我以为经过昨天的事  你会想睡觉的
I thought after yesterday, you'd want to sleep in.
睡不着  有很多工作要做
Can't. There's too much work to do.
我准备好了
I'm ready to do it.
我要鞭策自己
I want to push myself,
看看我的速度到底能有多快
find out how fast I can really go.
你说得对
You were right.
这不只是我一个人的事
This is not just about me.
开始工作吧
Let's get to work.
你...
Now, you...
有能力偷取闪电侠的力量
had the ability to steal the Flash's powers,
而我
and I...
很想知道
would love to know...
你是怎么做到的
how you did that.